ROHIT DARUNDE

Full Stack Web Developer

Gmail: rohitkumarme2618@gmail.com (+91) 7972009146 Nagpur ,India <u>rohit_portfolio_LinkedIn: rohitDarunde</u> Github: rohitkumar2618

Summary: Skilled in technology and coding with React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Node, and Express, experienced in modular solutions, front-end and back-end development, team leadership, and architectural decision-making.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

STOQ club pvt ltd

Apr 2024 - ongoing Nagpur (hybrid)

- Built a client-facing application delivering high-profit stock predictions using front-end technologies, API integration, and machine learning models, enhancing investment decisions and client satisfaction.
- Implemented dynamic user interfaces using React.js and demonstrated excellent communication skills by effectively presenting ideas and collaborating with team members.

Freelancer

Living Things

Jan 2024 - Mar 2024 Mumbai (Remote)

 Developed dynamic, responsive front-end interfaces, boosting user satisfaction by 45% and engagement by 30%, and utilized Vercel for deployment, reducing time by 40% and improving project delivery efficiency.

React Developer Intern

Ace Tech Ventures pvt Itd

July 2023 - Dec 2023 Nagpur (Onsite)

- Leading the engineering and development of an innovative frontend web application using HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, and JavaScript.
- Collaborated with the team, reducing website crashes by 30% through effective bug resolution.

PROJECTS

Me-snap (Social Media Web Application) [Live] [Code] react,tailwinds,typescript, app write cloud

 Led the development of Me-Snap, incorporating features like infinite scrolling, post liking, saving, and search, increasing daily active users by 35% and boosting engagement by 25%.

Gamefy [Live] [Code]

react, typescript, chakra ui

 Directed the development of a video game discovery app with user-centric features, boosting engagement by 30%, user satisfaction by 25%, reducing bounce rates by 20%, and increasing user retention by 40%.

Movies-flix [Live] [Code]

react and redux toolkit, restful API

 Developed a visually engaging platform for displaying movie information.

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Electronics and Telecommunication

Dr.Br.Ambedkar Technology University

2020 -2024 CGPA:8.11

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

- 5-star coder at Hacker-rank
- 6th institute ranked at the Geeks for Geeks platform.
- Skilled in problem-solving on Leet-code, Hacker-rank, GFG.

CERTIFICATION

- · Java Certification Course Skill up
- React.js Redux Firebase Mind luster
- Frontend Web Developer Mind luster
- · C++ and Java Course Disha Institute
- Paper Presentation at the International Conference
- Certificate of Appreciation for Extraordinary efforts & Dedication to create our College Magazine Sanskriti.
- HTML5 and CSS3 Course Pirple.

RESPONSIBILITY

- Co-Head of Dance Club
- Digital Content Developer of the IETE Student forum
- Executive member of Google Developer Student Club
- Documentation Co-Head of IIC Team